let's talk about how to pass to
Prudential first round interview
[Music]
what's up guys it's Mike from job ready
English here with another video to help
you get hired we break down the
recruitment processes and interviews for
World favorites companies to help you
pass their interview today we're going
to be talking about the insurance giant
credential and if you want more help to
pass your interview make sure you check
out our Prudential parsley interview
pack which you can find on the first
link down in the description below it
includes a 50 plus page research note
with up-to-date research from candidates
and what they found this year including
the recruitment process the most common
questions other questions that came up
sample answers as well as video courses
templates worksheets and other guides to
help you put together the very best
answers for your Prudential interview
this video is split up into three parts
part one we talk about credentials
recruitment process and what you can
expect part two we talk about the most
common questions that we found in our
research from clients who've been
through the process and have recorded
their answers in publicly available
sources and part number three we talk
about other questions that we came
across and what you can expect and how
you should think about answering them if
you want more videos like this please
make sure that you subscribe to the
channel like this video and drop us a
comment down below I do reply to all the
comments and I'm always really Keen to
understand how can we make our content
better how can we help you even more
with your upcoming interview so let's
start off with part number one and
prudentials recruitment process and what
you can expect candidates reported that
the recruitment process lasted two
months there was an online application
but there was no record about what types
of online tests you'd have to sit
through I would suggest it would
probably be a mixture of numerical
logical and situational judgment test
the interview details HR called to do
some screening about your resume
afterwards there were was and they
talked about your personality and
background if everything was fine you'd
then get a call for a next interview
which was a face-to-face interview as
well as a numerical assessment and based
upon our research from what candidates
have been through in 2022 no candidates
reported about there being an assessment
center part two let's talk about the
most common questions that candidates
were asked in 2022 for Prudential
question number one what are your career
goals so thinking about this question
it's really important to understand the
structure and hierarchy that you'll have
to go for a Prudential so say for
example you're looking at being an
insurance broker or an insurance agent
but you're already studying at
University and you actually want to go
on to be an actuary or design Insurance
products Prudential of course have a
wide range of products spanning across
lots of different markets now if you're
unsure about what that would be that's
really something that will be good for
you to look into another thing that I
recommend that you look to is are you
going to need any professional
qualifications or training as you go
through the process with Prudential if
so what would those be and what would it
involve question number two tell me
about yourself for an in-depth
explanation about how to answer this
question make sure you click the
thumbnail up above and you can also
download our free tell me about yourself
worksheet now if you've never done an
interview or you really struggle with
interviews I highly recommend that you
take this question and you practice it
first of all nailing a really good
personal introduction sets the tone for
the rest of your questions why because
an interview is quite a strange thing
we're not really used to selling
ourselves in an interview and also
selling it in a short space of time
essentially what you're trying to ask
for this question to say ah can you tell
me everything about you and your life in
two minutes please that's quite a
difficult thing to do without
preparation now we break down personal
introductions into six parts what are
you doing right now what have you done
in the past and bypassed I Define the
last three to five years so if you were
a master's student then what did you do
for your bachelor's if you're a
professional what was your last job or
your last two jobs part number three
what would you like to do so this is a
brief paragraph to say really that you
want to do this job at this company and
why part number four is you would talk
about work experience so you know what
work experience do you already have if
you don't have that what about
extracurricular activities clubs and
societies now if you're a graduate
watching this right now and you're in
the middle of your studies and you're
saying I don't have any experience
outside of my academics but now would be
a good time to go out and get some maybe
just go and volunteer at a charity shop
or join the salsa club and learn to
dance and become part of that committee
but really if you're just concentrating
on academics it will make it a little
bit more difficult for you when it comes
to interviews and finally you want to
talk about your skills and interests so
these could be the languages that you
speak the technical skills that you have
in terms of I.T or other software and
also your interests and hobbies and
here's a little bit of a tip or a bit of
a bonus why not end it on a hook you
might say well I also really enjoy
writing poetry and I recently
self-published my first book of poetry
what that does is it just creates a
talking point particularly for a
face-to-face interview one thing that I
always say to clients whenever I prepare
them is as soon as your face-to-face
interview becomes a conversation rather
than a question and answer session you
kind of know that you've got the
interview in the back question number
three why did you apply for this role
for an in-depth explanation and answer
to this question on a free worksheet
click the thumbnail up above you want to
answer this question in two parts and
you want to make sure that you've got
the job District action to hand the job
description is so important companies
write job descriptions because they're
basically telling you what is the
perfect candidate for this role now most
of the times job descriptions were
outlined more tasks or more
responsibilities than what is required
and that's absolutely fine you don't
have to meet all those tasks all those
responsibilities and all those skills
the first last part of your question
you're really going to want to answer
and say hey this is what I would need to
do in this job these would be my
day-to-day tasks now there's another
kind of reason for this is that when
you're being interviewed by someone from
HR a manager a director or doing a
higher view video interview everyone's
looking out for keywords they're trying
to listen for particular words and
phrases that are really important that
that candidate demonstrates and they
understand what it is that they're going
to be doing in the role so for example
if you're an actuary then I want to hear
that you'd be greater statistics that
you've got good mathematical ability
hopefully that you can use some kind of
software maybe at least Excel or you
have some experience around python or
SQL these are kind of the things that my
ears will perk up and I'll think oh that
person has the skills that are required
and importantly when you're talking
about the three or four skills that you
have that would make make you good at
the job just provide some experience and
proof to demonstrate to that employer
that not only am I saying that I can do
this thing but I actually have proof
because I've done that I've used that
skill at University or I did that in my
last job part number four why this
company again in-depth explanation of
free worksheet click the thumbnail up
above so when talking about why do you
want to work for Prudential the one
thing that you want to remember is to
pick out specific facts about the
company and I want to give you an
example from our research name with
access to over 4 billion people
Prudential PLC is an Asia and africa-led
group providing Health protection and
Saving Solutions to more than 18 million
customers we are building the capacity
to 50 million customers by 2025 and we
will do this by digitizing our product
services for pulse by Prudential at the
core and you can learn this from our
about us page they're our programs page
news page all links that we provide in
our research know so you want to pick
out five or six key facts about the
company making sure that they are
specific and if you really want to give
a great answer then make sure you relate
one or two of those facts to yourself do
you use a Prudential product do you know
someone who's worked at Prudential do
you like one of the Charities that they
give to relate it back to yourself and
inject a bit of Personality into your
answer part number three let's look at
some other questions and we've got four
here for you explain a time where you
manage multiple projects at once so this
is all about multitasking so a few
constraints to set for this I would say
try and pick two or three projects at
most why not four or five or more
because you have to explain them and
that's going to eat up into a lot of
your answer time most of the time when I
hear this answer it's from a graduate
who's talking about their coursework
their part-time job and maybe something
else perhaps it might be organizing
something for a club and Society or a
surprise that they were going to throw
for a friend and then really what you
want to do is break down the steps to
your answer so if I had to make a recipe
to create the product success that you
had what are the steps that I would need
to take well step number one I do this
step number two I do this so for example
at Job ready English we always have you
know a couple of different projects
running at the same time and what that
means is is that we have to be really
systematic in our approach so step
number one we may have a meeting to
discuss the project step number two we
would design a brief to outline the
project step number three we would
assign tasks to different members of the
team and so on and so forth but if we
design that as a recipe then somebody
else could come in and would know how to
go through the steps of doing that
project question number two why should
we hire you this is very similar to a
mixture of tell me about yourself and
why this job but what I would suggest is
or you want to concentrate on all of the
skills and experiences that you have
which match the job description
providing proof within that question
number three what are your strengths and
weaknesses this is a big question to
answer all in one first of all I
recommend that you choose two strengths
and one weakness choose any strengths
that match up with the skills that are
outlined in the job description now a
lot of people struggle with that
question of what are your weaknesses
what are you what is your greatest
weakness this is actually quite an easy
question to answer if you answer
truthfully and do a little bit of soul
searching within yourself so for me two
of my greatest weaknesses are
organization and time management as
somebody who I write professionally I
coach professionally I produce content I
run a business I sometimes can be a
little bit disorganized and that's not
even including all the stuff that I do
in my personal life so I have to really
work hard to be organized I plan my day
the night before I figure out exactly
what I'm going to do I try not to fit
too much into any one day because I know
that something's going to happen a
client may need to speak to me urgently
a member of the team may have a problem
that they need help with whatever it is
I kind of know that no day is ever the
same or just go smoothly so in line with
that that's how I stay organized I have
a diary I have a calendar I have a way
that people can book and spend time with
me we have a internal messaging portal
for all the members of the team and that
allows a certain level of organization
so what you'll notice that I did and
what you can do is be honest about your
weakness but demonstrate the lessons
that you've learned and the things that
you've put into place to overcome that
weakness question number four why did
you choose to join this industry this is
a fabulous question and I'm going to
read you out word by word the directions
that we've given in our research note to
help you with this question is pretty
common in finance related Industries
like Professional Services financial
services and banking make sure that
you're keeping up to date with
commercial news to be prepared to answer
this using the following steps keep up
to date with some basic business news
which is jargon free BBC business news
is a great place to start find websites
and Niche sites which are dedicated to
your chosen industry do this simply by
typing into Google your industry plus
industry news a top three to five
searches will be trade websites designed
specifically for Professionals in that
industry so for example if you want to
work in audit you would search for audit
industry news and find accountancy
age.com which you can subscribe to for
updates you can also set Google Alerts
you could use quora and Reddit I do
highly recommend reading other people's
experiences I'm sure that there's a
massive Reddit Community for actuaries
or insurance agents and you can read
about why other people do what they do
what they enjoy and what they don't
enjoy and that's a great way to give a
compelling answer to this question go
guys I hope that you enjoyed this video
if you watched it all the way through
please do me a massive favor make sure
you like the video drop a comment down
below even if it's just a thumbs up and
then I know that you've watched it let
me know if this video was helpful for
you what else could we have done to best
serve you wherever you are whatever
you're doing I wish you the best of luck
in your upcoming interview and in
finding a job see you later
[Music]